♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 23=
- Hurry!
- Run!
This way!
Fahai!
- Where is Master?
- To save us,
Master was killed
by the evil demon in the Forbidden Area.
That evil demon is out.
Master told you not to come back.
- Go!
- I'm not leaving.
- Go now!
- Go!
- I'm not leaving!
- Go now!
- Master!
Master!
I'll turn this place to ashes!
Die, all of you!
Everyone in Jinshan Temple, listen up!
Form the Water Shield Array,
to protect the people
and bring them into the temple.
White Snake,
you came just in time.
Today, I'll absorb your demon core.
Don't be so smug.
It's too early to say who will win.
Suzhen, don't waste your breath on him.
Suzhen!
Do you think you can stop me?
I truly don't get it.
With a mere mortal body,
how can you stand against me?
You killed my parents.
I will avenge you!
But I've killed too many people.
I can't remember. Apologies.
It seems today is truly my lucky day.
Soon, I will absorb
every last one of you
to achieve supreme power!
Dream on.
Qing.
What fine nourishment you two are!
I'll gratefully take them.
Suzhen!
You want to die?
No rush.
I'll grant your wish soon.
Qing.
Xu Xian, don't!
You'll get yourself killed!
I didn't expect that.
Even when you're in danger yourself,
yet you still want to protect others?
I missed one?
How dare you ambush me!
If you hadn't extracted me,
I wouldn't have lived like a monster.
Traitor, then I'll kill you as well.
Qing!
What's with that look?
I'm a demon.
I don't die that easily.
Don't talk.
I'll use the Leifeng Pagoda to heal you.
Remember,
don't activate
the wrong array this time.
(This thing never works
when I need it to.)
(It just malfunctioned again.)
(I told you not to come,
but you ignored.)
(You were in my barrier array,)
and now we formed a contract.
That means
I'm your...
S-Stop that!
Shut up.
Eat.
Get out.
Fahai, let me ask you,
if love is so wonderful,
why is it a trial?
Love is born from desire.
Desire arises from craving,
and the trial begins.
Don't fall asleep.
This is my final order to you.
You must not die.
Qing!
(I only hope you can comprehend
the great Dao soon,)
(achieve enlightenment in Buddhism,)
(and protect the peace
of the people in my stead.)
Master.
Master!
Fahai.
This is merely a wisp of consciousness
I left within you.
Your arrival here
proves you've enlightened.
I am truly gratified.
Master, so many people
have died out there.
All my fellows are dead.
Bai and Qing have been defeated too.
Master, what should I do?
Help me, Master!
- Please help me!
- Fahai.
I know you have much to say.
Amitabha.
Mortal bodies
will eventually reach their limits.
Ask not of cause and effect,
ask not of success or failure.
Just fulfill our duty in the present,
and protect those we can.
Go.
Amitabha.
You'll understand eventually
that everything you do now
will inevitably turn against you
in another way.
You and I have always been one.
Now my time has come to an end.
You are right.
This is the retribution I must bear.
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪